This case is a dangerous game of life and death.
The Lincoln Lawyer is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Brad Furman.
Mick Haller is a charismatic defense attorney who does
business out of his Lincoln Continental sedan.
Mick spends most of his time defending petty crooks and other bottom-feeders, so it comes as quite a surprise when he
lands the case of a lifetime: defending a Beverly Hills playboy who is accused of attempted murder.
However, what Mick initially thinks is an open-and-shut case with a big
monetary reward develops into something more sinister.
Mickey Haller, played by Matthew McConaughey.
Louis Roulet, played by Ryan Phillippe.
Frank Levin, played by William H. Macy.
Maggie McPherson, played by Marisa Tomei.
Ted Minton, played by Josh Lucas.
Val Valenzuela, played by John Leguizamo.
The Lincoln Lawyer is a 2011 American legal thriller film directed by Brad Furman and
written by John Romano, based on Michael Connelly’s 2005 novel of the same name.
The film stars Matthew McConaughey as Mickey Haller, a Los Angeles criminal defense
attorney who operates out of the backseat of a chauffeur-driven Lincoln Town Car.
Ryan Phillippe, Marisa Tomei, Josh Lucas, John Leguizamo, William H.
Macy, and Bryan Cranston appear in supporting roles.
The story follows Haller as he takes on the case of a
wealthy client accused of assault.
As the trial progresses, Haller uncovers unsettling parallels with a previous
case, forcing him to confront ethical dilemmas and hidden truths.
The Lincoln Lawyer was released by Lionsgate Films on March 18, 2011.
It received generally positive reviews from critics
and grossed $87.7 million worldwide.
The film was nominated for Best Action or
Adventure Film at the 38th Saturn Awards.
The film explores themes of california, prostitute, based
on novel or book, judge, attempted murder.
The tone is emotional and intense.